Mss.B.St65p
American Philosophical Society
- Series VII. Works by Stokes
  - Passive Active Immunization of New Born Infants, Undated
    ...by oral vaccination with attenuated poliomyelitis virus.
  - Pediatrics immunization as a developing mirror of nature, 1970
  - Personal, 1924-1970; 7.0 folders
  - Place of Continuous Venoclysis in Pediatric treatment, Undated
  - Pocono Lake Preserve, 1957-1961
  - Poliomyelitis, 1945-1956, undated
  - Practical approach to the use of rubella vaccine, 1970-1971
  - Presentation of Honorary Fellowship, 1972
    to Margaret I. Handy, M.D.
  - Repeated Plasmapheresis..., 1957
    ..in the same person, a rationale for modern bloodletting.
  - Research Grant Application, 1960-1963
  - Research Plan, Undated
  - Review of certain recent developments in the knowledge of respiratory infections, 1935
  - RH studies, 1946
  - Smolens, Joseph, Undated
    Combined therapy in the treatment of human serum infected with bacteriophage; Combined use of ultraviolet irradiation and beta propiolactone...
  - Studies of the Nutritional Value..., 1938
    ...and digestibility of soft curd milk within the gastro-intestinal tract.
  - Studies on Influenza, 1938
  - Studies on Measles, 1942, undated; 3.0 folders
    Results following inoculation of children with egg-passage measles virus; Results of chance and planned exposure to unmodified measles virus in children previously inoculated with egg-passage measles virus; Experimental disease in man and monkeys; Measles produced with chick-egg virus in monkey and man.
  - Studies on the use of aureomycin in hepatic disease, Undated
    With John Farquhar, Coleman Whitlock, Jr., Lewis W. Bluemle, Jr., Joseph M. Gambescia.
  - Study of a Reaction following the Intramuscular Injection of whole blood, 1936
  - Clifford D. Sweet Clinics and Lecture Program, 1953-1954
  - Testimony in Campbell vs. Triangle publications, 1967-1968
  - Textbook of Medicine, 1945-1963
  - Textbook of Pediatrics, 1940-1963
  - Thayer Lectures, 1966-1967
  - Turn of the Centry (of Progress) for Children, 1955
  - Use of Gamma Globulin, Undated
    ...from large pools of adult blood plasma in certain infectious diseases.
  - Use of Magnesium Sulfate, Undated
    ...avertin and sodium amytal with the drinker respirator in the treatment of experimental strychnine poisoning. With Ben T. Bell.
  - Usefulness of immune serum globulin in viral hepatitus, 1971
  - Value of passive immunization in certain viral diseases, 1967
  - Viral Hepatitis in the Newborn, 1956
  - Visit to Russia, 1954-1958; 4.0 folders
  - Visit to Russia--Photographs, 1958
  - W-133 Project, 1962-1965; 2.0 folders
  - White Paper: Children's Hospital and the University of Pennsylvania, 1959
- Series VIII. Works by Others
  - Abstracts, Undated; 2.0 folders
  - Altemeier, W.A., 1957
    Pathology and Physiology of PVP Rentention, Subcommittee on Shock, Progress report.
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1969-1970
    Who Shall Live? Man's Control over Birth and Death.
  - Ames, Mary
    With William Hamilton. A Clinical study of a lotion containing hexachlorophene for the care of the skin of the newborn.
  - Anderson, H.D., et al, 1964
    Clinical use of dried fibrinogen and the risk of transmitting hepatitis by its administration.
  - Barnouw, Eric, 1946
    Children's hospital.
  - Beall, Gildon N., 1957-1959
    Histamine metabolism in human disease. Liquid scintillation counting of Histamine-C14 and its metabolites. With Paul P. VanArsdel, Jr.
  - Blackfan Lecture, 1956
  - Boyd, T.E., Undated
    Passive immunization--a review of the literature
  - Burckhardt, Sigurd, 1964
    How not to murder Caesar.
  - Burnette, C.H., Undated
    Information System for Hospital Planning
  - Chang, Te-Wen, 1970
  - Chapple, Charles, 1939
  - Church, Charles F., 1938
    Diet and Resistance to Infection.
  - The Clinic...a Philosophic Melodrama, Undated
  - Cohen, Seymour S., 1955
    The death of bacteria as a function of unbalanced growth.
  - Cuddy, T. Edward, 1959
    Daland Fellowship report
  - Davis, William J., et al, Undated
    A Study of Rubella Immunity and Resistance to Infection
  - Dryden, Hugh L., 1960
    Prospects for Space Travel. Penrose Lecture, American Philosophical Society.
  - Eddy, Walter, 1937
    Data bearing on the effect of topical application of vitamin A and D to the skin.
  - Esselstyn, Caldwell B., 1966
    Outlook for group practice-prepayment, direct service plans during the next 20 years.
  - Exner, F.B., 1957
    Fluoridation of Public Water Supplies
  - Faber, Harold K., Undated
    The Evolution of Poliomyelitic Infections
  - Fanconi, G., Undated
    The Varying Sensitivity to Vitamin D.
  - Farley, David, 1948
    Vitatropin M.
  - Fulton, George P., 1955-1956
    Evaluation of Plasma Expanders. Subcommittee on Shock, Progress Report.
  - Gitterings, J. Claxton, 1936
  - Gocks, David J., 1967
    Experimental viral hepatitis in the dog
  - Grant, Lester, 1948
    Enzymes and Headlines, on reporting scientific news.
  - Guilbert, Paul, Undated
    With David Baker, L.A. Barness. Fat retenton in infants fed breast milk and humanized cow's milk.
  - Hammon, Wm McD, Undated
    Suggested plans for a field trial to determine the effectiveness of of gamma globulin in the prophylaxis of poliomyelitis.
  - Hartman, Frank W., 1956
    Chemical inactivation of the virus of serum hepatitis.
  - Hemmendinger, Miriam, Undated
    Admit Parents at all Times
  - Henle, Gertrude, Undated
    With Werner Henle, Susanna Harris. The Serological differentation of mumps complement-fixation antigens.
  - Hummeler, Klaus, Undated
    The role of the virus diagnostic laboratory in public health.
  - Hyde, Richard W., 1965
    Factors affecting the transfer of gas from the lungs into the blood in normal human subjects.
  - Inter-University Seminar, 1955
    Psychological aspects of the sexual orientation of the child.
  - Janeway, Charles A., 1955
    Genes, Proteins and Diseases
  - Kirber, Maria Wiener, Undated
    With Werner Henle. A comparison of influenza complement fixation antigens derived from allantoic fluid and membranes.
  - Koelle, George B., Undated
    Psychopharmacology
  - Koop, C. Everett, Undated
    Neuroblastoma in Childhood
  - Koprowski, H., et al, Undated; 2.0 folders
    Clinical investigations on the use of attenuated strains of poliomyelitis virus as a method of immunization of children with living virus. Immunization of children by the feeding of living attenuated type I and type II poliomyelitis virus and the intramuscular injection of immune serum globulin.
  - Krogman, Wilton Marion, 1957; 3.0 folders
    Viken Sassouni. Syllabus in Roentgenographic Cephalometry
  - Leftwich, Charles, Undated
    With George Mirick, Gertrude Henle. The apparent failure of material from chick embryos inoculated with hepatitis virus to immunize aganist unadapted virus.
  - Lieberman, E. James, Undated
    A case for the small family.
  - Lilienfeld, Abraham, 1952
    With Irwin Broos, Philip Sartwell. Observations on an outbreak of infectious hepatitis in Baltimore during 1951.
  - Mack, Pauline Beery, Undated
    Measurement of Mineral Density of Bones
  - May, Edgar, 1972
    Narcotic Addiction in Great Britain.
  - McDougall, Clarice, Undated
    A clinical evaluation of abnormal enzyme content in the pancreatic juice of children.
  - McGinness, A.C., 1947
    Diphtheria. Schick Testing and Immunization.
  - Mudd, ____, Undated
  - Ogden, Eric, 1935
    Review of literature of vaso-tonic properties of shed blood.
  - Park, Edwards A., Undated
    With Richard Follis, David Gould. Evaluation of X-ray film for diagnosis of rickets
  - Paul, John R., 1944
  - Planned Parenthood, 1942
    Syllabus: A suggested outline for teaching medical indications and techniques of conception control.
  - Purdue Frederick Company, 1969
    In vitro and in vivo studies of the microbicidal effects of PVP-I formulations.
  - Quastel, J.H., 1957
    Investigations of factors involved in absorbtion...
  - Ramsey, R. Paul, 1971
    Screening: an ethicist's view
  - Religion and Medicine, 1954
  - Rose, Catharine, Undated
    With Robert Luchi, R.E. Norris, Paul Gyorgy. Mono- and disaccharides in the growth of lactobacillus bifidus and its mutants.
  - Rose, Elizabeth Kirk, 1952
    The role of a health department in training pediatric residents. With John A. Rose.
  - Rose, John Andrew, 1960-1961, undated; 8.0 folders
    Folder 1-Child development and object relationship; Folder 2-Emotional deprivation cycle and social progress; Folder 3-Impact of psychological retardation and neurological handicaps on psycho-social development in early childhood; Folder 4-New approaches to the treatment of disturbed youth; Folder 5-Prevention of mothering breakdown associated with perinatal contingencies anticipating loss of the infant or of his capacity for future normal development (1960); Folder 6-Primary prevention; Folder 7-Retrospective and prospective studies on the implications for the primary prevention of mental disorders in childhood or parent-child relationships arising from the birth of children with congenital abnormalities; Folder 8-Schizophrenia in childhood: a commentary (1961)
  - Rubin, Mitchell, 1939
    Studies in experimental anaphylaxis.
  - Scott, Joseph P., 1938
    Studies on swine influenza virus; Swine influenza associated with hog cholera.
  - Slagle, Alma Dorothy, 1967
    The role of the Quaker physicians in the American colonies.
  - Somers, Anne R., 1962, undated; 2.0 folders
    Financing of Child Care in the Philadelphia Area. Report for grant W133.
  - Sonis, Meyer, Undated
    A Tale of Two Specialties
  - Specht, Heinz, 1962
    Survey of Various Japanese Biomedical Research Institutions.
  - Starr, Isaac, Undated
    A survey of Ballistocardiography, with Abraham Noordergraaf.
  - Stein, Gertrude, Undated
    My Last about Money
  - Stockholm, 1955-1956; 2.0 folders
    Study Group on Pediatric Education
  - Surgenor, Douglas, 1953
  - Talmadge, David, 1957-1958
    Mechanism of the Antibody Response
  - Tarizzo, M.L., 1957-1966
    List of bibliographic references on trachoma. Medical officer, Virus Diseases unit, World Health Organization.
  - Taub, S.J., 1969
    Allergy: Adverse reactions following administration of human Gamma Globulin
  - Torres, Francisco, 1953
    With James Wheller, Isabella Romans. A study of infantile diaper rash.
  - White, Kerr L., 1966
    Organization and delivery of personal health services: public policy issues
  - Wolman, Irving J., Undated
- Series IX. Printed Material, 1930-1972
  - Community Medical News and Concerns, 1.0 box
  - Diseases, 3.0 boxes (1 ln. ft.)
  - Hospitals, Medical Research, Public Health, 2.0 boxes (1 ln. ft.)
  - International Medical News, United Nations, 1.5 boxes (1 ln. ft.)
  - Newsletters, newspaper clippings, periodicals, 1.5 boxes (1 ln. ft.)
  - Organizations, Foundations, 2.0 boxes (1 ln. ft.)
  - Schools, 1.0 boxes (1 ln. ft.)
- Series X. Graphics
  - Copper plates
  - Glass lantern slides
  - Photographs